Guide to the Malcolm Goldstein Papers MSS.350
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series V: Commercially Released Media
  - Subseries A: Sound Recordings
    - "Le Canard 18" Musique Action 23 Festival Des Musiques Nouvelles; Centre Culturel Andre Malraux, May, 2006 (Box 38)
      Contents: "Pere Ubu, Eugene Chadbourne, Phil Minton, Jimmy Carl Black, Mike Cooper, Pat Thomas, Pascal Comelade & le Bel Canto Orchestra, Paul Lovens, K.K. Roll, Sean Meehan, Dave Liebman, Susan Alcorn, Joey Baron, Camel Zekri, Evan Parker, Fred Van Hove, Johannes Bauer, Jeranium, Jean-Francois Pauvros, Noel Akchote, Daunik Lazro, Michel Doneda, El Cabrero, Jean-Marc Montera, Le Quan Ninh"
    - "Cd Connection"; New Arts Program, undated (Box 38)
      Includes works by "Robert Ashley, Connie Beckley, Glenn Branca, Jon Gibson, Philip Glass, Malcolm Goldstein, Joan La Barbara, Meredith Monk, Steve Reich, Peter Van Riper"
    - "Chants Caches" Malcolm Goldstein, John Heward, Rainer Wiens; Ambiances Magnétiques, 1999 (Box 38)
      Contents: "Trio 1" (3:17); "Trio 2" (8:51); "Trio 3" (15:08); "duo 1" (6:33); "Trio 4" (8:59); "Duo 2" (8:18); "Trio 5" (12:59); "Trio 6" (4:52)
    - "Ensemble SuperMusique" including Goldstein piece, 2016 (Box 38)
      Currently Available.
    - "Goldstein plays Goldstein: live at decapo in Bremen '94"; Ingo Ahmels, 1994 (Box 38)
      Contents: "Ishi/ man waxati soundings" (21:14); "Gentle rain preceding mushrooms" (13:52); "Qerneraq- our breath as bones" (16:13); "Soundings for solo violin" (18:22)
      Duration: 69 minutes
    - "Hardscrabble Songs" Malcolm Goldstein, Quatuor Bozzini; In Situ, 2004 (Box 38)
      Contents: "My feet is tired but my soul is rested" (11:21); "Soundings" (10:40); "Hardscrabble Songs" (13:15); "Where are we going when we're standing still, looking backwards ?!" (15:18); "A New Song of many faces for In These Times" (19:20)
    - "John Cage: Variations II, Eight Whiskus, Music for Two, Ryoanji" with Malcolm Goldstein and Matthias Kaul; Wergo, 1999 (Box 38)
      Contents: Variations II: realisation for violin and glass harmonica by Malcolm Goldstein (19:52) -- Eight whiskus: for violin (5:07) -- Music for two: for violin and percussion (29:27) -- Ryoanji: for voice and percussion (voice part trans. for violin by Malcolm Goldstein (19:51)
    - "KlangZeit Munster 2006"; Grenzgange, 2006- 2007 (Box 38)
      Credits: Roderik de Man, Shih, Bernd Alois Zimmermann, Rajesh Mehta & Rohan de Saram, Qin Wenchen, Svoboda-Scodanibbio-Kiedaisch, Ulrich Krieger, Stephan Froleyks, Global Village, Anton Webern, Giacinto Scelsi, Malcolm Goldstein, Valdis Zilveris, Olaf Pyras & Erhard Hirt"
    - "Les Accords Intuitifs," Ensemble Supermusique, 2016 (Box 38)
    - "Live at Fire in the Valley" Malcolm Goldstein; Eremite, 199-? (Box 38)
      Contents: Soundings I (4:45) -- from "Configurations in darkness" (17:51) -- When the river overflows (18:38) -- My feet is tired but my soul is rested (17:44) -- Soundings II (2:41)
    - "Live in Puget-Ville" Malcolm Goldstein, Barre Phillips; Bab-ili, 2006 (Box 38)
      Contents: "MGBP (9:40); "GBPM" (18:26); "PBGM" (7:45); "BMPG" (13:36); "MPGB" (11:52); "Pourquoi pas- Beep" (9:33)
    - "Malcolm Godlstein and Matthias Kaul: Exploratorium Berlin", 2014 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Missa Amissa, Malcolm Goldstein and Fred Lonberg-Holm, 2022 (Box Shared Fales 045, Audiocassette 350.0167)
    - "Monsun" Malcolm Goldstein, Peter Niklas Wilson; True Muze, 1998 (Box 38)
      Contents: "Monsun vibrations I / Goldstein, Wilson -- From "Configurations in darkness" / Goldstein -- Kraniche im Zweireiher / Wilson -- The space of the bass / Wilson -- Soundings for solo violin: Hamburg, 1996 / Goldstein -- Monsun vibrations II / Goldstein, Wilson -- Monsun afterthoughts / Goldstein, Wilson"
      Original format: (1 sound disc) (64 min.): digital; 4 3/4 in.
      Duration: 64 minutes
    - "Montreal Telegraphe: le son iconographe" Montreal Telegraph: Sound as iconographer; Chaostechnologues Occurrence, 2000 (Box 38)
      "CD-ROM and CD-Audio published on the occasion of the exhibition presented at Montreal Telegraphe from May 4 to 28, 2000";"Installations et performances."
      Original format: 2 computer laser discs: sd., col.; 4 3/4 in. System requirements for PC Windows 95/98 or NT 4.0: Pentium 166 MHz processor or faster; 32 MB of RAM (64 MB recommended); 50 MB of uncompressed hard drive space; 16X CD-ROM drive or faster; 100% Sound Blaster-compatible sound card; 800 x 600 display; thousands of colors; MS-mouse campatible.; System requirements for Macintosh: MAC OS 7.1 or higher; 8X CD-ROM drive; 20 MB of free RAM; 800 x 600 display; thousands of colors.
    - "Musicworks: 56" Sound/Image, 1993 (Box 38)
      Contents: "Composition for violin and voice (1991) / Iva Bittová (17:10) -- Hot rolled steel (1985-89) / Barbara Benary (13:18) -- Tongues of my mother's teaching (1988) / Malcolm Goldstein (8:02) -- Collage no. 2, Viet flakes (1967) / James Tenney (10:13) -- Chinese song (1991) / Ida Bittová (2:56) -- Canyon shadows: Stones (1991) / Robert J. Rosen, Peter Christensen (13:07) -- On the way (1991) / R.I.P. Hayman (12:46)."
      Original format: (1 sound disc) digital 4 3/4 in
      Duration: 78 minutes
    - "Musicworks: 64", 1996 (Box 38)
      Contents: "L'ivress de la vitesse (excerpts) / Paul Dolden (7:52) -- Harmonium / Gayle Young (8:40) -- Utopianism / Jack Behrens (6:27) -- Melody #5 (for Musicworks). Note #2 / Tentatively, A Convenience (0:01) -- Jade Mountain soundings / Malcolm Goldstein (13:05) -- Resurrected fields (excerpts) / Adrian Ivakhiv (11:23) -- Koan / James Tenney (22:13)."
    - "Musicworks 77: Community Resonances", 2000 (Box 38)
      Contents: "Rainbow Valley / Stephen Parkinson (1:28) -- Chorale / James Tenney (2:48) -- Qernerâq: our breath as bones / Malcolm Goldstein (20:04) -- For the love of Pete / Wrist Error (10:56) -- Prepared guitar #1 / Josh Thorpe (3:41) -- Blues for scurvy / Wrist Error (8:50) -- For magister Zacharias / Marc Sabat (10:09)."
    - "Musicworks 78: Gesture and Interaction", 2000 (Box 38)
      Contents: "From Configurations in darkness: (1995) / composed and performed by Malcolm Goldstein (12:43) -- Trousseau--True nature: (2000). Excerpts from improvisations, Bridle party; Teacups; Wild birds; Chapel hum / by Urge -- Parallels: (1998) / composed and performed by Rob Wannamaker (8:20) -- It were another: (1998) / composed and performed by Malcolm Goldstein (10:28) -- Lullaby for Daisy Pauline: (1979) / by Pauline Oliveros (2:28) -- Improvisations for piano and extensions: (2000) / composed and performed by David Cronkite (13:08)."
    - "Musicworks 93", 2005 (Box 38)
      Contents: "Where are we going when we're standing still, looking backwards? (16:48); Approaching the wall (7:42) / Malcolm Goldstein -- Warm weather with soundballs / Eric Chenaux and Marla Hlady (20:11) -- War hospital (excerpt) (3:43); John & Michael (excerpts) (2:48) / re-recording mix by Shelley Craig -- Kawachi, audio spectral / Emmanuelle Loubet (12:14)."
      Duration: 63 minutes
    - "Organic Oboe" Joseph Celli; O.O. Discs, 1991 (Box 38)
      Contents: "Sky: S for J: for five English horns (without reeds) / Joseph Celli -- Spiral: for a soloist [vocal or instrumental, and short-wave radio] / Karlheinz Stockhausen -- Extended oboe: for oboe and electronic tape / Elliot Schwartz -- A summoning of focus: for wind instrument / Malcolm Goldstein."
    - "Pieces of the Past: By Philip Corner for the Violin of Malcolm Goldstein"; Pogus Productions, 2011 (Box 38)
      Contents: "Philip Corner's piece for Malcolm Goldstein by Elizabeth Munro (20:43) -- Gamelan antipode/s with Piece for string instrument #3 (18:10) -- Gamelan Maya (16:52) -- The gold stone (13:55) -- Piece for string instrument #5 (3:02). Credits: Malcolm Goldstein, violin; Philip Corner, piano (3rd work)"
    - "Portrait Montreal" Quatuor Bozzini; QB, 2004 (Box 38)
      Contents: "Pulau dewata / Claude Vivier; arr. Michael Oesterle (11:47) -- Quatuor à cordes II. Divertimento serioso; Round, catch and canon club; Divertimento buffo; Mr. Birdcage's ground; Tombeau; Musique sur laquelle il n'est pas interdit de danser / Jean Lesage (18:03) -- Daydream mechanics V / Michael Oesterle (11:23) -- A new song of many faces for in these times / Malcolm Goldstein (19:03). Credits: Quatuor Bozzini (Clemens Merkel, Nadia Francavilla, violins; Stéphanie Bozzini, viola; Isabelle Bozzini, violoncello)."
    - "Quatuor d'Occasion" Malcolm Goldstein, Josh Zubot, Jean Rene, Emile Girard Charest, 2014 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - A. "Riverrun"; B. Wergo, 1999 (Box 38)
      Contents: "CD 1: Voicings. Muoyce / John Cage -- Pas de voix / Charles Amirkhanian -- Le corpsbis / Henri Chopin -- Lautaggregat = Sound aggregate / Carlfriedrich Claus -- erst verbun (alpha) / Alvin Curran -- Gebet = Prayer / Gerhard Rühm -- Artikulationen = Articulations / Franz Mon -- Fa:m' ahniesgwow / Hans G Helms -- Erweiterter Schwitters: eine Transplantation = Extended Schwitters: a transplantation / Stephan von Huene -- Spaltungen = Divisions / Ernst Jandl, Friederike Mayröcker -- Celebration of NO / Sorrel Hays -- Penthesilea aubade: nach Heinrich von Kleist / Carlo Quartucci -- Andromache: nach Motiven des Euripides und Sartres / Hans Ulrich Humpert -- Ophelia and the words / Gerhard Rühm, Klaus Schöning -- Danton's death: after Georg Büchner / Linda Mussman -- --nach einer Lektüre von Orwell = --after a reading of Orwell / Mauricio Kagel -- Elegien = Elegies / Werner Cee -- Andere Räume = Other spaces / Robert HP Platz -- For Julian / Alvin Curran -- Voicings / Hans Otte -- Radio. Hörtext 16 / Ferdinand Kriwet -- SOS / Barry Bermange -- 7448: eine kolumbische Phantasie = A Columbian fantasy / Paul Carter -- Sdreamings / Josephine Truman -- Bean sequences / Alison Knowles -- Das Hörspiel des Bibers: ein Testament = The beaver's Hörspiel: a testimony / Jerome Rothenberg -- Ishi/Timechangingspaces / Malcolm Goldstein -- Vox humana / Jack Body -- Für Stimmen = For voices / Anne Tardos, Jackson MacLow -- Humayun's tomb / Pauline Oliveros -- Satie's rose cross as a revelation / Philip Corner -- Das Hsin hsin ming des Seng Ts'an / George Brecht -- Roaratorio / John Cage. Contents: CD 2: Soundscapes. Ohrbrücke/Soundbridge Köln - San Francisco / Bill Fontana -- The Vancouver soundscape / R. Murray Schafer -- Metropolis Venedig. Venezia exaudi / Marielouise Franke -- Sound painting Cologne / Joan La Barbara -- Nah und fern / Mauricio Kagel -- Metropolis Buenos Aires / Francisco Kröpfl -- Ji-virus / Michael Riessler -- Metropolis Tokyo: im Rennschritt / Emmanuelle Loubet -- Satelliten-Klangbrücke/Satellite sound bridge Köln - Kyoto / Bill Fontana -- CCU, metropolis Calcutta / Klarenz Barlow -- Metropolis New York / Richard Kostelanetz -- La ville: Die Stadt: Metropolis Paris / Pierre Henry -- Klanglandschaft Ruhrgebiet / Richard Ortmann, Raimund Fleiter, Ralf R. Wassermann -- Lingua X tichon oder die Bedeutung des Weges / Thomas Schulz -- Alles ein atmendes Buch: Klanglandschaft Kumaon / Peter Pannke -- Forests/Wälder / Douglas Quin -- Schweigende Landschaft / Ronald Steckel -- Arctic: Kristallklar / Charles Morrow -- Virginia reel / Susan Stone -- Ear circus no. 1 / Randy Thom -- Matera Sassi / Nicola Sani -- Metropolis Arles / Arsenije Jovanović -- From our dreams and visions / Sarah Hopkins -- Mungo / Ros Brandt -- Sound shadows / Sorrel Hays -- Sweeney's vision / Frank Corcoran -- Topography of a sound mind / Malcolm Goldstein."
      Duration: a) 71 minutes b) 72 minutes
    - "The Seasons: Vermont" Malcolm Goldstein; Experimental Intermedia Foundation, 1998 (Box 38)
      Contents: "Robert Black, double bass; Mark Steven Brooks, flutes, guitar, & percussion; Joseph Celli, oboe, English horn, & ocarina; Malcolm Goldstein, violin; Tom Guralnick, saxophones & vaccuphones; Brian Johnson, vibraphone & percussion; Kenneth Karpowicz, intensified vocalizing & accordion (1st work); Malcolm Goldstein, violin (2nd work)."
      Duration: 60 minutes
    - "The Seasons: Vermont For Magnetic Tape Collage and Instrumental Ensemble" Malcolm Goldstein; Folkways Records & Service Corp, 1983 (Box 38)
      Contents: "Summer (14:50) -- Autumn (10:15) -- Winter (19:40) -- Springs (5:00)."
    - "The Seasons: Vermont For Magnetic Tape Collage and Instrumental Ensemble" Malcolm Goldstein; Smithsonian Folkways Archival, 2007 (Box 38)
    - "The Smell of Light" Malcolm Goldstein, Matthias Kaul; Nurnichtnur, 2004 (Box 38, Box Shared Fales 085, Sound-disc-cd 350.0168)
      Contents: " It were another: for violin and voice (12:27); That is poetry as: for violin and percussion (1:33) / Malcolm Goldstein -- Revolver: for hurdy gurdy and voice (11:41) / Matthias Kaul -- Concerning melody: for violin and percussion (13:14) / Goldstein -- Last! Movement: for violin and percussion (16:57) / Kaul -- Good mourning moon: for violin and hurdy gurdy (10:56) / Goldstein, Kaul. Credits: Malcolm Goldstein, violin; Matthias Kaul, percussion."
    - "Soil" Malcolm Goldstein, Masashi Harada; Emanem, 2006 (Box 38)
      Contents: "Premonition (5:12); "Soil under tree" (8:23); "Dropping out of sky or rock" (4:42); "Bitter Pride- In the midst of Green Plain" (2:48); "Portentous Revelation" (6:08); "Come ride and ride to the garden" (4:44); "Relentlessly Curious" (2:50); "Cliff, Ravine, Rock" (3:13); "A Garden" (1:09); "Romanticism in Relation to Life" (9:07); "Micro Lyricism" (5:23); "Wind and Mirror" (4:06); "Wind and Mirror 2" (1:54); "Secret Sharer" (0:46)
      Duration: 61 minutes
    - "Solo" Malcolm Goldstein; Forum Neue Musik Christianskirche/ Ottensen, October 2010 (Box 38)
      Contents: "Excerpts from 'Fragments of the Wall'" (8:00); "Ishi/man waxati Soundings" (13:18); "My feet is tired but my soul is rested" (8:07); "Out of nowhere and there to again" (5:34); "Soundings for solo violin" (8:21); "Zugabe" (1:19)
    - "A Sounding of Sources" Malcolm Goldstein; New World Records, 2008 (Box 38)
      Contents: Configurations in darkness (35:57) -- Ishi/timechangingspaces (20:01) -- Ishi/"man waxati" soundings (13:16). Credits: Variously: Malcolm Goldstein, violin, voice; Radu Malfatti, trombone; Philippe Micol, bass clarinet; Philippe Racine, flute; Beat Schneider, violoncello.
      Duration: 79 minutes
    - "Sounding the New Violin" Malcolm Goldstein; Nonsequitur, 1991 (Box 38)
      Contents: Eight whiskus / John Cage (5:21). -- Sounding the fragility of line / Malcolm Goldstein (13:23). -- Portrait of Malcolm / Pauline Oliveros (12:17). -- Trinity / Ornette Coleman (12:28). -- (gamelan) The gold stone / Philip Corner (13:45). -- Koan / James Tenney (11:59). Credits: Malcolm Goldstein, violin.
      Duration: 72 minutes
    - Soweto Stomp, 2016 (Box Shared Fales 085, Sound-disc-cd 350.0170)
    - "Speaking in tongues" Ganesh Anandan, Malcolm Goldstein, Rainer Wiens; Canada Council of the Arts, 2003 (Box 38)
      Contents: "Twenty Fingers" (6:22); "Dream Algebra"(5:57); "Voyage en train" (5:54); "RaMa" (8:02); "Foreign Tongues" (9:07); "Up North" (4:11); "Fra Ma Ga Ra" (7:03); "Lullaby" (3:59)
      Duration: 51 minutes
    - "Ten Years of Essential Music"; Monroe Street Music, 1997 (Box 38)
      Contents: Music of the spheres / Johanna M. Beyer (Alvin McCall, cello; Charles Wood, lions roar) -- in memorium-- Kit Carson (opera) [excerpt] / Robert Ashley (Janet Axelrod, Alexandra Calas, J. Cobe, Melissa Gardner, Paul de Jong, John Kennedy, Jerome Kitzke, Ben Manley, Sean Meehan, Maxim Moston, Kendall Pigg, Mark Suter, Charles Wood) -- A green pine / Peter Garland (Dora Ohrenstein, soprano; Guy Klucevsek, accordion) -- Chant / John Kennedy (John Kennedy, Eric Kivnick, Charles Wood, percussion) -- Merce [excerpt] / Christian Wolff (Maya Gunji, John Kennedy, Eric Kivnick, Michael Pugliese, Charles Wood, percussion) -- The seasons: Vermont. Winter [excerpt] / Malcolm Goldstein (Robert Black, contrabass; Joseph Celli, oboe & English horn; J.D. Parran, clarinets; Malcolm Goldsten, violin; John Kennedy, Eric Kivnick, percussion; Ben Neill, mutantrumpet -- Snake dance no. 2 / Kyle Gann (Maya Gunji, John Kennedy, Eric Kivnick, Charles Wood, percusion; Kyle Gann, keyboard) -- Land's shadow, visible world / Charles Wood (Frank Balluffi, John Kennedy, Gregg Linde, Charles Wood, percussion) -- Land's shadow, visible world / Charles Wood (Frank Balluffi, John Kennedy, Gregg Linde, Charles Wood, percussion)
    - "Variations II," "Eight Whiskus," "Music for two", "Ryoanji", 1999 (Box Shared Fales 085, Sound-disc-cd 350.0171)
    - "Video Ears Music Eyes" Joseph Celli, Jin Hi Kim, Malcolm Golstein, Ulrich Krieger, Brian Johnson, Grupo de Musica Folklorica del Peru; O. O. Discs, 1995 (Box 38)
      Contents: 36 strings: for komungo and 5 channels of video (1992) (15:41) -- 8 mallets four Brian: for solo xylophone and 3 channels of video (1986) (12:17) -- Andes: for 7 Peruvian musicians and a mountain of televisions (1990) (19:56) -- Video sax: for sopranino saxophone & 5 channels of video (1993) (13:07) -- Violin & video: for solo violin and 3 channels of video (1988) (12:14) Credits: Jin Hi Kim, komungo (1st work); Brian Johnson, percussion (2nd work); Grupo de Music Folklorica del Peru (3rd work); Ulrich Krieger, saxophones (4th work); Malcolm Goldstein, violin (5th work)
      Duration: 74 minutes
    - "Without Compression: neue musik fur blockfloten" Trio Diritto: Jeremias Schwarzer, Martin Hublow, Ines Rasbach; Cybele, 1998 (Box 38)
      Contents: Without compression: (1997) / Rolf Riehm (12:26) -- Renaissance: (1997) / Myriam Marbe (10:39) -- Et in Arcadia ego: (1996) / Anatol Vieru (9:17) -- Au cœur du silence--: (1995) / Violeta Dinescu (9:11) -- Round of talks: (1994) / Georg Kröll (4:58) -- Veränderungen: (1993) / Stefan Thomas (6:10) -- In the beginning-- so also, the end: (1997) / Malcolm Goldstein (22:34). Credits: Trio Diritto (Jeremias Schwarzer, Ines Rasbach and Martin Hublow, recorders).
      Duration: 75 minutes
    - "Yes," Malcolm Goldstein and Rainer Wiens, 2016 (Box 38)
  - Subseries B: Video recordings
    Subseries B is comprised of commerically released video discs.
    Material is arranged alphabetically by title.
    - "Cry of Ecstasy: the art works of Junko Chodos with improvised musical response by Malcolm Goldstein, a film by Robert Primes", 2005 (Box 38)
      x
      Original format: (1 videodisc) digital 4 3/4 in.
      Duration: 22 minutes
    - "Malcolm Goldstein and Matthias Kaul im Exploratorium Berlin"; Exploratorium Berlin, April 21, 2008 (Box 38)
      Duration: 2 hours 20 minutes
    - Sylvia Safdie: "Act/Shadow", 2006 (Box 38)
      Duration: 11 minutes
    - Sylvia Safdie: "Dust", 2009 (Box 38)
      "Amzrou is a small village in souther Morocco. In the interior of an abandoned synagogue, thrown dust combines with light."
      Duration 4.5 minutes
    - Sylvia Safdie: "Line", 2007 (Box 38)
      " This video is part of an ongoing series, which explores the relationship between image/sound, sound/image. This is the result of working very closely with contemporary musicians such as: Malcolm Goldstein, John Heward, Dana Reason, Joe McPhee, Liu Fang, Dominique Duval and others."
      Duration: 8 minutes
    - Sylvia Safdie: "Reflections: A Trilogy (demo)", 2007- 2009 (Box 38)
      Duration: 14 minutes
    - "Vertiges" Fortier Danse-Creation, 2012 (Box 38)
  - Subseries C: Vinyl Sound Discs
    Subseries C is comprised of commerically released vinyl sound discs.
    - "Early Electronic/ Tape Collage Music"; Alga Marghen, 2008 (Box 39)
      Contents: Sheep meadow (6:34) -- Images of Cheng Hsieh (15:51) -- It seemed to me (5:42) -- Judson #6 piece (6:43) -- Illuminations from Fantastic gardens: for vocal ensemble / text, Arthur Rimbaud (13:03).
      Original format: (1 sound disc) analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo.; 12 in.
    - "Full Circle Sounding" Malcolm Goldstein; Kye, 2015 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - "Musical Elements 10th Anniverrsary Recording"; CRI, 1987 (Box 39)
      Contents: Passage I / Wyner (8:48) -- A breaking of vessels, becoming song / Goldstein (15:10) -- Fantasy etudes / Lerdahl (14:08). Credits: Musical Elements; Robert Dick, solo flute (2nd work); Daniel Asia (1st-2nd works) and Robert Beaser (3rd work), conductors.
    - "One Hundred Years of Soundings" Philip Corner and Malcolm Goldstein; Alga Marghen, 1998 (Box 39)
      LP 1: Side One: Tongues og my Mother's Teaching (20'12") LP 1: Side Two: (gamelon) Antipode (12'00); Configurations in Darkness (07'36") LP 2: Side Three: An Enactment of Absence (18'36") LP2: Side Four: [Untitled: Malcolm was guest in Philip's loft at 75 Leonard St. in New York City where they played together on December 1, 1991] (21'15")
      Original format: (2 sound discs) analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo.; 12 in.
    - "Organic Oboe" Joseph Celli; Stereo O. O. Records, 1979 (Box 39)
      Contents: Sky:S for J: for five English horns (without reeds)(1976) / Joseph Celli. -- Spiral: for soloist (1968) / Karlheinz Stockhausen. -- Extended oboe: for oboe & electronic tape (1973-74) / Elliott Schwartz. -- A summoning of focus: for wind instrument (1977) / Malcolm Goldstein. Credits: Joseph Celli (live and taped oboe, English horns, voice, and other sounds and modifiers).
    - "The Seasons: Vermont for Magnetic Tape Collage & Instrumental Ensemble" Malcolm Goldstein; Folkways Records, 1983 (Box 39)
      Contents: Summer (14:50) -- Autumn (10:15) -- Winter (19:40) -- Springs (5:00). Credits: Performed by various musicians with various instruments.
    - "Soundings for solo violin" Malcolm Goldstein; Real Art Ways, 1980 (Box 39)
      Credits: Improvisations performed by Malcolm Goldstein.
    - Stones: Dreams, Geoffrey Hendricks with Philip Corner, 2019 (Box Shared Fales 046, Folder 2)
    - "Vision Soundings" Malcolm Goldstein; Malcolm Goldstein, 1985 (Box 39)
      Contents: From center of rainbow, sounding: violin solo (18:20) -- Vision tree fragment: maple tree limb and vocal solo (17:20).
    - "The Winds Rise in the North" Harlen Gaber; Titanic, 1976 (Box 39)
      Ensemble: Violin: Linda Cummiskey, Malcolm Goldstein, Hathy Seplow; Viola: Stephen Reynolds; Cello: David Gibson
- Series VI: Non-commercially Released Audio
  Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  Series VI comprises non-commercially released audiocassetes and sound discs. It is split into two subseries containing performances and interviews. Each subseries is described more fully below.
  - Subseries A: Performances
    Subseries A is comprised of non-commercially released audiocassettes, sound discs, and one reel. More information about the known contents of each media item is listed below.
    Materials are arranged alphabetically by title as designated on the object.
    Material is currently unavailable. Please contact Fales Library for further information.
    - Acoustic Art (Horspiel) Works, September 26, 1985; February 18, 1988; April 22, 1998; ID: 350.0001 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0001)
      1) "The Edges of Sound WIthin" (19'55") 2) "Ishi/time changing spaces" (19'54") 3) "as it were, another" (21'08") Westdeutscher Rundfunk Cologne, Studip Akustische Kunst
      Original format: 1 sound disc: digital; 4 3/4 in.
    - Acoustic Art (Horspiel) Radio, 1993- 1997; ID: 350.0002 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0002)
      1) "Between (two) spaces" (37'55") Westdeutscher Rundfunk, Cologne. Studio Akustische Kunst 2) "Regarding the Tower of Babel" (25'10") Hessischer Rundfunk Ensemble fur Neue Musik. Premier: TheaterHaus Frankfurt
    - "As it were, another" Studio Akustische Kunst, WDR Koln, 1996- 1998; ID: 350.0003 (Box 40, Media ID: 350.0003)
      "As it were, another" (1998) radio/acoustic art. "As it were" (1996) Malcolm Goldstein: Violin. Robert Black: Cello. Charles Wood: Percussion. World premier Merkin Concert. "Gentle rain preceeding mushrooms (in memorium John Cage)"